# **Patrick Gordon**

#### pgpatrickgordon@gmail.com | github.com/paddygord

Programmer for over ten years, currently a professional software developer and research engineer at Hadean. I am the lead developer of Hadean's distributed spatial simulation engine, Aether, and our spatial technology. Working at a startup from the very early stages I have taken on a wide range of responsibilities, including growing our engine development team, researching and designing the spatial technology, and developing it using agile methods.

CEO, Hadean: "I've never seen someone come into a company and have as big an impact as that"

VP Eng, Hadean: "He gets s\*\*\* done"

# **Key Skills**

#### Communication

- Writing many technical but accessible blog posts for our company blog
- Teaching and onboarding within the company
- Communicating externally in a pre-sales role with Partners and Investors
- Promoting the company at events, including Game Developer Conference
- Collaborating with Game Developers, Physicists, Biologists, Engineers and many Software Engineers

#### **Development**

- Using my expertise in spatial partitioning and simulation I started and continue to lead development of Aether (Hadean's distributed spatial simulation engine)
- At Createc I developed a spatial processing, storage, and visualisation pipeline on resource constrained hardware
- My final year project at Cambridge was a performant sparse voxel octree raycasting system, for desktop GPUs
  - Dissertation link
- In my spare time I have built:
  - A compiler for a new programming language intending to be used for high performance code on a variety of accelerators (multicore CPUs, SIMD coprocessors and GPUs)
    - LLVM, GLSLang, Lex/Flex, Yacc/Bison, C++
  - A network visualiser for processes distributed across machines
    - Javascript, D3.js, Linux iproute2 tool SS
  - An experimental (tiny) soft 8 bit processor core on an FPGA.
    - Verilog, FPGAs
  - A boot loader in x86 assembly
    - x86 Assembly
  - A dynamic website backed by a database
    - Go, Javascript, HTML, CSS

#### Tools

- Expert: C, C++, GLSL and GPU programming, Linux, Git, Make
- Experienced: Python, Bash, Javascript, HTML, CSS, CMake, Meson
- Learning: Rust, Nix, Verilog and FPGAs, x86 Assembly

#### Libraries

- Game Engines and Simulation: PhysX, Eigen, Unreal Engine, OpenGL
- Robotics and Computer Vision: ROS, SLAM,

• Deep Learning: Tensorflow, Caffe,

### **Education**

#### University of Cambridge, Selwyn College October 2013 - June 2016

• Computer Science, BA (Hons) - 2:1

#### Nelson Thomlinson School, Cumbria (State Comprehensive) September 2008 - June 2013

- Maths A (taken one year early highest grade available)
- Further Maths A\*
- Physics A

# **Employment**

#### **Hadean September 2018 - Present**

• Hadean was a small startup when I joined, looking for market fit in three verticals. After quickly getting up to speed on the HadeanOS technology they were building, within two weeks I started developing Aether for Gaming, Simulation and Science. We quickly found traction in gaming after going to GDC with a small demo, using Aether as an MMO backend. We accelerated development and I helped grow the team, hiring and onboarding new engineers. I grew a huge amount by being the lead developer, getting the chance to work closely with all different business functions.

### Createc July 2016, September 2016 - September 2017

• I joined Createc in summer 2016 for an internship and, due to my excellent work and attitude, within three days was offered a permanent post. I gained valuable experience working with ROS and real-time and embedded systems on drones with many sensors including radiation sensors. These systems are currently in use in extremely challenging environments at Fukushima (Japan) and Sellafield (UK). I developed a deep-learning system, to classify X-Ray images of baggage as threat or benign, using Caffe on a multi GPU system, for deployment on an embedded system. I used computer vision algorithms on a lightweight, embedded, aerial platform. I worked on a scanner system for industrial purposes, to accurately map, and present potentially hazardous environments remotely. One of my favourite parts of working for Createc was the mentoring, for example teaching debugging a device driver. My proudest achievement while working there was developing a system to ingest point cloud data from many sensors, fuse it into a single cloud, store the tens of millions of points efficiently, pass it through processing steps, and then display it to a user interactively, based on the hardware position sensor data. This system is in use on multiple different projects that are central to the company.

#### University of Cambridge, Computer Science October 2013 - June 2016

• Due to my outstanding A-level results and passion, I had the opportunity to study at Cambridge, attaining a 2:1. Among my favourite courses were Machine Learning, Advanced Rendering, Bioinformatics, Comparative Architectures, Computer Vision, and Information Retrieval, I found these particularly rewarding because they focused on understanding large, complex, real-world subjects. In the second year, I worked with a team (contributing a large part of the code, experience and bugfixes) to develop a game system for an external company, Frontier. The client feedback was that the product and teamwork was excellent. My final year project was on an advanced voxel ray-tracing pipeline for desktop GPUs, which was written in C, OpenGL and GLSL and which showed a performance increase of 25x over the benchmark version of the renderer.

#### Citrix August 2012

• In August 2012, I worked in the XenClient team of Citrix, a multinational virtualisation software provider. At Citrix, I was asked to write an automated test suite for network connectivity, for an interface I had never seen, in a language I had never used before (Python). I swiftly learned the fundamentals of the interface and language. After completing the test suite, my work went into production while I was there. Unbeknown to me,

my supervisor had bet his colleagues that I would not be able to complete this task in the time set. I confounded his expectations by learning the new language and completing the whole task in less than two weeks.

# **Interests**

- National Cipher Challenge Whilst still at school I reached the final round for the last three years and won two awards.
- Robotics Engineering and Space Science | participated in a two week Imperial College Summer School when I
  was 11. This was led by Dr Richard Palfrey, who said "Patrick... was able to articulate his ideas extremely well.
  Patrick's final presentation (on robotics) was excellent."
- *UK Mathematical Challenge* Run by Leeds University. Starting with the regional final, I achieved a Gold Award and four Silver awards.
- I am keen on Bouldering, Badminton and Cycling, being part of the Selwyn 2nd team for Badminton for 2 years.

## References

Available upon request